Last week, the worst nightmare of the
four horsemen of the apocalypse came
true. Alibaba became a frontier AI lab
with announcements made during their
Absara conference, which if you've never
heard of is like the Super Bowl for
shape rotating aspie comrades with the
announcement of a $52 billion
three-phase road map. They've made one
thing clear. They read the comments. Oh,
and they're all in on the great race to
artificial super intelligence. In
today's video, we'll take a closer look
at that road map, break down all of the
new models they released, and show how
their ultimate plan is to become the
Android of the AI era. It is October
3rd, 2025, and I hope you're ready to
learn Chinese. As a teenage boy, I
learned that the best things in life
come in threes, and that's why I was
revved up when I heard Alibaba announced
their three-phase road map to ASI. Phase
one is emergence of intelligence, where
AI achieves generalized understanding by
stealing, I mean, learning, vast amounts
of human knowledge. This is where we
were a few years ago. The phase two is
autonomous action where AI can learn to
use the languages and tools humans do in
order to offer some assistance. This is
where we are today. And phase three is
selfiteration where AI can connect to
the physical world and learn on its own.
This is where we either all die or live
in a gluttonous utopia and Alibaba
thinks we'll be there by 2032. I have my
doubts, but they're shipping like
they're addicted to creatine laced with
aderall, so it might come true. Their
biggest release of the conference was
Quen 3 Max. The base model has over 1
trillion parameters and was pre-trained
on 36 trillion tokens using its mixture
of experts architecture. I know every
time I mention a benchmark, an intern in
the tenderloin gets mugged, but for
being a non-thinking model, Quen 3 Max
Instruct scores pretty well on the
standard benchmarks and there's a
reasoning variant that's currently being
trained that does as well. And the most
impressive release of the week may be
Quen 3VL. Their vision language model
designed to process and understand
visual input like images and videos. And
it currently sits at the top of this new
awesome benchmark, Clockbench. It turns
out just like Gen Z, current Frontier
models struggle with reading an analog
clock. But Quen 3VL is now the tallest
dwarf with 39% accuracy. And it gets
bonus points for being as powerful as it
is while being open source and open
weight. And if vision and language
aren't enough, they also released Quen 3
Omni, their multimodal model, which can
see, hear, read, and talk. And that
means it's now possible to create
highquality AI girlfriends that are free
and open- source. But before you go and
do something foolish like that, you need
to understand how this AI stuff works at
a low level with Brilliant, the sponsor
of today's video. A hard truth is that
code is useless if you don't understand
the math and computer science behind it.
Brilliant helps you master these
concepts with interactive lessons that
you have to learn by doing, not just
watching video lectures. I'd highly
recommend taking their thinking and code
course where you'll learn how to think
from first principles like an
experienced programmer. Most
importantly, you'll develop critical
thinking skills through problem solving,
not just memorizing. Try Brilliant for
free by visiting brilliant.org/fireship
org/fireship or scan the QR code on
screen to get 20% off a premium annual
subscription which gives you unlimited
access to everything on Brilliant. This
has been the code report. Thanks for
watching and I will see you in the next
one.
[Music]